HARDIK RAVAL

C7/6, Police headquarters, Dani limda, Ahmedabad

Co: +91- 9586492825, 8200450138 | hardikraval192@gmail.com

Career Objective

A Project Sales & Marketing professional with 4+ years of experience. knowledge of managing projects across different business functions and Cross flow teams end-to-end. Strong team building capability while maximizing performance and delivery. A good understanding of project planning, including scope management, Breakdown Structures, estimating and scheduling. Looking for an opportunity in the role of Project Management where I can further grow under the guidance of excellent people.

Work Experience

Citizen Industries Ltd.- A member of DAIKIN group, Ahmedabad

Job Profile: Sales & Marketing

Software skills: SAP-S4/HANA SD, MS Office 365,

• Responsibilities: Sales Targets, Project Management, Client Meetings, Business development, Product Marketing. Responsible for Maintaining SD data in SAP, Preparing MIS & Business Review Meetings, Carrying out Presentation Activities, Documentations as per SOPs to meet company ISO standards.

• **Experience:** September, 2020 to present.

Key Tasks and Activities:

- Responsible for performing all sales activities within a Project Management cycle Right from Receiving inquiries, Quotations, Negotiations, Client visits & Meetings, make approvals Delivery Schedules, Payment activities & customer services for end-to-end project.
- I am looking after punching data for Business partners, Sales Orders, Quotations, Outbound deliveries and Creation of Billing activities in SAP.
- Achieving sales targets, booking targets, Billing targets & many other continuous improvements which I have completed within deadlines efficiently.
- Adding to that preparing and maintaining MIS & BRM registers and giving presentations on regular intervals to Management is a key activity keep everything under control.
- Writing non-technical Standard Operating Procedures (SOPs). Worked as Internal admin for endto-end implementation of SAP S4/HANA ERP system at Citizen Industries ltd. – A Member of DAIKIN group with IBM.

- Acquired experience in working for different modules such as SAP SD, SAP MM, etc. in SAP S/4 HANA.
- Provided training to the end users and ensured they are comfortable working on the SAP software.

Melt Engineering, Ahmedabad

• Job Profile: Design & 3D Printing Engineer

• **Software:** Solidworks 2018, Cura, Repetier, Autodesk Mesh mixer, PTC Creo, MS Excel

• Responsibilities: 3D modeling of industrial products, Model parts by reverse engineering,

Checking for errors in existing design and make the design viable, 3D Modeling from

2D drawings, create 3D printable files, Make 3D Prints.

• Experience: 24 months. (JUNE,2018 to Aug 2020)

• Key Tasks and Activities:

- o Preparing **Delivery schedules** of Prototype projects as per client requirements.
- o Preparing Quotations, Closing orders and providing design solutions to clients.
- Converting clients' prototype projects, starting from CAD design to developing satisfactory prototypes. End-to-end product developments.
- O I have used CAD software skills and developed many standard designs for various fields which include IOT companies, Architectures, Local Manufacturers. personalized USB enclosures, Health equipment, Multi-tasking Table designed for ISRO, PCB enclosures, Can and bottles with nonplanar mating, Plastic products like spoon for baby feeding are some of the projects I have completed successfully
- I have been part of the workshop organizing in SAMVAAD-2018, Silver Oak College. I have also organized my own workshop on "3D Printing and Importance of Design" for "TECHXTREME-2019", GANDHINAGAR INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY which is going to be in first week of March-2019.

Internships

Undergraduate Engineering Trainee - R.B. INDUSTRIES

Dec, 2017 - Dec, 2017

• I have assisted a Production Engineer by coordinating him in developing operational strategies to achieve production. I have planned and coordinate production engineering processes on daily basis to produce high quality products.

Undergraduate Engineering Trainee - Makson Pharmaceuticals(I) Pvt.Ltd Jun, 2017 - Jun, 2017

• I have worked as a junior Mechanical engineer trainee and I have been given tasks to develop and implement a PRODUCTION FLOW CHART on project of manufacturing a AUTOMATIC

PACKING MACHINE by the senior engineers. I have communicated with all manufacturing departmental heads and workers to know every single aspect. I have analyzed and executed the data and developed a full production flow chart proficiently with my communication skills and technical knowledge.

Academic Details

Degree/Course	University / Board	Year of Passing	CGPA / Percentage
BE, Mechanical Engineering	Gujarat Technological University	2018	8.31
HSC	GSEB	2014	77.33
SSC	GSEB	2012	92.40

Academic Project

Multiple Diameter Pipe Bender - Assistant Prof. Dhruval V. Patel

Jul, 2017 - Nov, 2017

• I have done a project on developing a multiple diameter pipe bending machine under the guidance of Mr. Dhruval Patel. I have completed all the GTU PMMS activities online by submitting the work within time limits satisfyingly. I have studied 10 different patents related to our title and based on that with the help of group members have prepared a CAD MODEL of our project in solidworks to develop a machine which can different diameter pipes at different bending

Diameters with manual operations

Skills

- Excellent verbal and interpersonal skills with preference given to demonstrated client liaison aptitude.
- Demonstrated experience of **effective stakeholder management** with a variety of stakeholders and the ability to **communicate effectively** with said stakeholders
- Good problem solving, decision making, communication and negotiation skills at all levels
- Strong working knowledge of **Microsoft Office**, with intermediate skills in Word, Excel and PowerPoint
- Engaging with operational and project management teams to ensure that correct skills, parts and resources are available in order to meet customer demand
- Managing project budgets and tracking project cost
- A good understanding of **Project Control, including cost control, schedule adherence**, risk management and change management
- Experience gathering and managing client requirements

Technical:

SOFTWARE	INSTITUTE	STUDENT ID	YEAR
AutoCAD	CADD CENTRE, SURENDRANAGAR	M180351713	2018
SOLIDWORKS	CADD CENTRE, SURENDRANAGAR	M180351713	2018

COURSE	INSTITUTE	GRADE	YEAR
CCC	TCIL - IT	A	2014

- Comfortable in communicating with English, Gujarati and Hindi
- I have cleared A1 level in GERMAN language with CEFR C1.
- I have cleared IELTS with CEFR C1.

ACHIEVEMENTS

Cultural:

• I am one of the heads of well-known students DISCIPLINE COMMITTEE of my college and we have successfully done 3 cultural festivals and concerts with the help of 150+ volunteers in my college.

Educational:

- I was in top 25 Lineup students in GSEB board results.
- I have scored 9.64 SPI with overall 8.31 CGPA having second rank in last term

Sports:

• I am a member of our class cricket team who have won gold medal in Feb 2017 and silver medal in Feb 2016 and Feb 2018 among 48 Teams.

I hereby declare that the above written particulars are true to the best of my knowledge and belief.